In Python, you can create lists really quickly and
concisely with a cool tool called List Comprehensions.
In the cities example from earlier,
we created a list of capitalized cities from the cities list in a for loop.
With a list comprehension,
we can get the same result like this.
List comprehensions allow us to create a list using a for loop in one step.
You create a list comprehension with brackets including
an expression to evaluate for each element in an iterable.
This line called city.title for
each element in cities to create each element in the new list.
Notice this part looks just like the first line of a for loop without a colon,
and the action you want to take on each element is taking on the element here,
and append it to this new list.
In the list comprehension,
we don't need to create a new list
beforehand and append to it like we would in a for loop.
List comprehensions are not found in other languages,
but are very common in Python.
Here's another example that creates a list of squares from 0 to 64.
This line called X to the power of two for every element
in range nine to create each element in the new list, squares.
We can write this as a list comprehension like this.
Again, we are just looping through each element in
this iterable and evaluating this expression to get each new element in our list.
You can also add conditionals to list comprehensions.
After the iterable, you can use the If keyword to check a condition in each iteration.
In this example, X to the power of two is only evaluated if X is even.
This gives us a list only including squares of even numbers.
If you want to add an Else,
you will get a syntax error doing this.
If you'd like to add Else,
you have to move the conditionals to the beginning of
the list comprehension right after the expression like this.
Details on why this is the case are in the notes below.